我带蜡烛跟我妈的蕾丝桌布
I'll get candles and my mom's lace tablecloth.
既然是瑞秋的生日…
And since it's Rachel's birthday...
…我想我煮一条鲑鱼
...I thought I'd poach a salmon.
怎么样嘛？
What?
我要问为什么每次开派对 你都要水煮东西啊？
Question. Why do we always have parties where you poach things?
你想总掌食物委员会吗？
You want to be on the food committee?
问题二，为什么每次派对 都要有食物委员会？
Question 2. Why do we always have parties with committees?
为什么不买些披萨跟啤酒 大家高兴就好了嘛？
Why can't we just get pizza and beer and have fun?
对, 我同意. 我认为有趣的派对大家都参与才有趣
I agree. Fancy parties are only fun if you're fancy on the inside.
我不确定我们会快乐
And I'm not sure we are.
你们不想要点特别的？
You don't want it to be special?
很好，你们爱怎么样就怎么样
Fine. You can throw any kind of party you want.
乔伊，那是假的
Joey,they're not real!
在这里面数英里远的地方才是我的，这是假的
I start miles beneath the surface of these things. They're fake.
看，像汽车喇叭
See? Honk,honk!
像给小丑看的色情片
Wow,it's like porno for clowns!
六人行 第2季 第22集 两个派对
The One With Two Parties
我跟瑞秋的妹妹讲了 她们都不能够来
Neither of Rachel's sisters can come.
那我还得邀请迪伦 艾玛，还有香浓
I still have to invite Dylan and Emma and Shannon Cooper.
不要香浓
No Shannon Cooper.
为什么呢？
Why not her?
因为她…
Because she....
会偷东西
She steals stuff.
又或许她不会偷东西，但他跟她上床后就没再打电话给她了
Or maybe she doesn't and Joey slept with her and never called her back.
乔伊，那太过份了
Joey,that is horrible.
我喜欢她，好吗？
Hey,I liked her.
或许太喜欢了
Maybe too much.
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜我只是怕了
I guess I just got scared.
对不起，我不知道
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
没想到有人会吃这一套
I didn't think anyone would buy that. Okay!
亲爱的，好玩吗？
Hi,honey. How did it go?
地狱般的毕业典礼
It was the graduation from hell.
我表弟是靠足球奖学金 上“地狱大学”的
My cousin went to hell on a football scholarship.
这本来应该是个快乐的场合
It's supposed to be a joyous occasion.
我妹妹从大学毕业了 谁也没想到
Nobody thought my sister would graduate from college.
证明了一个长岛女孩为了一部赛利卡跑车（丰田）会做什么
It's a testament to what a girl from Long lsland will do for a Celica.
到底怎么了？
What happened?
我父母的事情
My parents happened.
他们只需要坐在同一个体育馆 骄傲地微笑…
All they had to do was sit in the same stadium,smile...
…绝口不提离婚的事 但不！
...and not talk about the divorce. But no!
开幕致词到一半时 他们就吵得不可开交了
They got into a fight during the commencement address.
主教还得停下来 叫他们两个住口
Bishop Tutu actually had to stop and shush them.
你们知道好消息是什么吗？
You know the good news?
我接着可以帮人 倒八小时的咖啡
I get to serve coffee for the next eight hours.
那我们可以不要邀请她父母
I guess we don't invite her parents.
只邀她妈妈，怎么样？ 为什么？
-How about just her mom? -Why her mom?
因为我已经邀了
Because I already invited her.
你邀了史戴西吗？
Did you ask Stacy Roth?
不，不能邀她
Can't invite her.
她也会偷东西
She also steals.
还有她的室友
So does her roommate.
这是生日蛋糕的蜡烛 那生日蛋糕呢？
Here are the candles. Where's the birthday cake?
我们不吃生日蛋糕
We're not having birthday cake.
我们吃生日馅饼
We're having birthday flan.
什么？
Excuse me?
是一种传统墨西哥蛋奶冻点心
It's a traditional Mexican custard dessert.
不错呀
That's nice.
生日快乐，瑞秋，来些粘粘的东西
Happy birthday,Rachel. Here's some goo!
格林医生
Dr. Greene!
老天啊，是瑞秋的爸爸
Oh,my God! It's Rachel's dad.
你来做什么？
Why are you here?
怎么了？女儿生日 老爸过来看看也不行吗？
The father can't see the daughter on her birthday?
不…老爸当然可以
No,no,the father can.
但是由于我是她室友 我可以告诉你她不在
But since I am the roommate,I can tell you she's not here.
我会转告她你来过了 所以，再见
And I'll pass along the message. Okay? So bye-bye.
你们开派对呀
You're having a party.
不，不是派对啦
No,no,not a party.
只是一群 瑞秋认识的人的惊喜聚会
Just a surprise gathering of some people Rachel knows.
这是菲比，钱德，乔伊 太多人了我记不住
-This is Phoebe,Chandler and Joey. -I'll never remember all that.
你们怎么计划的？
So what's the deal?
瑞秋回来，大家跳出来尖叫 是不是这样子？
Rachel comes home,people pop out and yell stuff? Is that it?
这不是 你的第一个惊喜派对吧？
This isn't your first surprise party,is it,sir?
莫妮卡
Hi,Monica.
中餐馆的伙计 他忘了拿菜单了
The Chinese menu guy. Forgot the menus.
所以基本上只是个中国人而已
So basically,just a Chinese guy.
格林医生，你跟我来好了 我们把外套放瑞秋床上
Dr. Greene,come with me. We'll put your jacket on Rachel's bed.
好吧，那听起来是需要两个人的工作
All right. That sounds like a two-person job.
我的天，你刚才怎么了？
Well,my goodness! What was that?
真对不起，我以为你是瑞秋 可是我们还没准备好
Sandra,I thought you were Rachel. We weren't ready for you yet.
你以为我是瑞秋？ 对啊，你看起来好年轻
-You thought I was Rachel? -Yes,because you look so young.
而且基本上你们两个都是… 白种女人
And because you're both,you know,white women.
我好想念你们 我应该把外套放卧室吗？
Oh,I missed you kids. Should I put my coat in the bedroom?
不，交给我好了 那就谢了
-No,I'll take that for you. -Oh,well,thank you.
真是个绅士啊
Such a gentleman. Thank you.
看起来真棒，这么有节日气氛 那么多汽球
It all looks so nice. So festive. All the balloons.
我过来的时候碰见一两件怪事
Oh,the funniest thing happened to me on the way here.
我在开… 太棒了
-I was driving -That's great!
我等不及你说完 因为我要去厕所
I can't wait to hear the rest,but I have to go to the bathroom.
跟我来
Hey,come with me.
什么？ 就像我们是姐妹
-What? -lt will be like we're gal pals.
你知道，像在餐厅 会很好玩的，来吧…
You know,like at a restaurant. It'll be fun! Come on.
天啊…
Oh,my God. Oh,my God. Oh,my God!
想一想，快想一想
Think. Think.
杰克跟克里斯会怎么做？（肥皂剧《三人行》的主角 克里斯瞒着家人与杰克做室友）
What would Jack and Chrissy do?
你的外衣安全放在床上了…
Okay,now that your coat is safely in the bed
我们现在可以回客厅了
We can come back out in the living room.
对了，乔伊，钱德，我想你们应该带格林医生到你们那边去
Joey and Chandler,it's time you take Dr. Greene over to your place.
对，完全正确
Yes,absolutely.
为什么？
Why,again?
因为派对在那边呀，呆子
Because that's where the party is,you goon!
这边只是准备区 对…准备区而已
-See,this is just the staging area. -Right,it's the staging area.
这个很显然放错地方了
This is clearly in the wrong apartment.
好吧，你们这些去一号派对
All right,you guys are off to party number one.
而你们呢…
And you....
去二号派对
You are off to party number two.
继续走，继续走，快
All right,let's keep it moving,let's keep it moving.
你至少送些女的来我这边好吗
At least send some women to my party.
是罗斯，好…
Okay,that's Ross. All right.
他们来了
Okay,they're coming.
谢谢你美妙的晚餐
Thank you for such a wonderful dinner.
谢谢你出生
Thanks for being born.
谢谢你这对漂亮的耳环 真的好美
Thank you for my beautiful earrings. They're perfect.
我爱你
I love you.
你想的话可以拿去换别的
Now,you can exchange them if you want,okay?
现在我更爱你了
Now I love you even more.
惊喜…
Surprise!
天啊…
Oh,my gosh!
哇！
Wow!
天啊…妈
Oh,my God. Mom!
太棒了
This is so great!
生日快乐，瑞秋
Happy birthday,sweetie.
你…我完全不知
You! I had no idea!
真的？ 不，我知道的
-Really? -No,I knew.
好
All right.
各位，桌上有吃的跟喝的
There's food and drinks on the table.
现在去对面 乔伊跟钱德那边，去呀
Go across the hall. Right now,Joey and Chandler's.
为什么？ 去就是了
-Why? -Just go.
真怪
Weird.
惊喜！
Surprise!
生日快乐，小甜豆
Happy birthday,sweet pea.
爸爸
Daddy!
他们都来了，两个都来了？
Both of them are here? Both of them? Both of them are here?
我们可以再数一次
Well,we could count again?
我无法相信有这种事
I can't believe this!
这太荒唐了
You know,this is ridiculous.
这是你的生日，你的派对
This is your birthday,your party.
我说把他们放在一起，如果他们应付不来的话，谁在乎？
Let's put them together. If they can't deal with it,who cares?
我在乎 就是你
-I do. -That's who.
你不要紧吧？
Are you gonna be okay?
我根本就别无选择嘛 我可以往好的方面想啊
I don't really have a choice. I can look at the bright side.
我有两个生日派对 还有两个生日蛋糕
I get two birthday parties and two birthday cakes.
其实只有…
Well,actually...
…一个生日馅饼
...just one birthday flan.
那是一种墨西哥蛋奶冻点心
It's a traditional Mexican custard dessert.
你去跟莫妮卡讲比较好 她是食物委员会的人
Talk to Monica. She's on the food committee.
有个女的刚刚走过来跟我说 “我要你，丹尼”…
Some girl just walked up to me and said,"I want you,Dennis"...
…然后给了我一个舌吻
...and stuck her tongue down my throat.
我爱这个派对
I love this party!
我有个排球问题 排球？
-Quick volleyball question. -Volleyball.
我们在你房间弄了个球场
We set up a court in your room.
你不是真的喜欢 那个灰灯，对不对？
You didn't like that gray lamp,did you?
刚才有个女人给我一个舌吻 我根本就没听你说话
A woman stuck her tongue down my throat. I'm not even listening to you.
丹尼… 她在叫我了
-Dennis! -Okay,that's me.
亲爱的，你陪我爸一下，好吗？ 我要去跟我妈讲一下话
Can you keep Dad occupied? I'm gonna talk to Mom for a while.
那我用什么话当… 当开场白
Do you have any ideas for any openers?
你只要避开“我是那个上你女儿的人”…
Stay clear of "I'm the guy that's doing your daughter"...
…就不会有问题了
...and you should be okay.
我要你们一个人拿一张纸…
I want you to take a piece of paper
拿去 然后写下你们最尴尬的回忆
Here you go. And write down your most embarrassing memory.
请各位在用完墨水笔之后 把笔盖盖上…
When you're not using the markers,put the caps back on them...
…不然的话，笔会干掉的
... because they will dry out.
格林医生
Hi,Dr. Greene.
血管外科游戏中…
So how's everything in the...
…的一切…
...vascular surgery...
…都还好吗？
...game?
那不是游戏，罗斯 今天有个女人死在我手术台上
It's not a game,Ross. A woman died on my table today.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那就是我工作的好处
That's the good thing about my job.
因为我在工作台上的那些恐龙 都已经死了
All the dinosaurs on my table are already dead.
听着，各位 我并不是故意要烦你们的…
Listen,I don't mean to be a pain about this...
…但我注意到 你们刚刚有些人只是套上
... but I've noticed some of you are just placing them on.
你们应该是要用力按…
You want to push the caps...
…按到喀的一声为止
... until you hear them click.
甘瑟
Gunther!
你要去哪里啊？
Where you going?
我…我只是在想，或许我…
I was sort of thinking about maybe
不…你不能走 不，这很好玩
No! No,you can't go! No,this is fun.
来嘛…我们才刚开始 来，这是你的笔
We're just starting. Here's your marker.
听着，你想走就走好了
If you want to go,just go.
不，她会再吼我
She'll yell at me again.
好吧，我可以把你弄出去
All right,I can get you out.
什么？
What?
等一下我们来个转移注意力
In a minute,I'll create a diversion.
到时候，你赶快朝门走 不要回头
When I do,walk quickly to the door and don't look back.
我想来杯喝的 我去帮你拿
-I think I need a drink. -I'll get it for you.
你要喝什么？ 苏格兰威士忌
-What do you want? -Scotch.
好，我十秒钟之内 会带着你的苏格兰威士忌加冰块回来
I'll be back in 10 seconds with your scotch on the rocks in a glass.
纯（有“很棒的”意思）
Neat!
酷！
Cool.
纯的，不加冰块
Neat,as in no rocks.
我知道
I know.
罗斯，你上哪儿去了？
Hello,Ross! Where have you been?
我一直在洗手间
I have been in the bathroom.
避开那些鲑鱼慕斯
Stay clear of the salmon mousse.
纯苏格兰威士忌
Scotch neat.
那是瑞秋她爸喜欢喝的
That's Rachel's father's drink.
我也是，很纯正，不是吗？
Mine too. Isn't that neat?
苏格兰纯威士忌
Scotch neat.
我先失陪了
Would you excuse me?
你想溜到哪里去呢，先生？
Where are you sneaking off to,mister?
我要去拿我外套里的香烟
I'm getting my cigarettes.
不…
No.
什么意思啊？
What do you mean "no"?
因为那边是准备区
See,because that's the staging area.
你一去的话 你对派对的幻影就都成空了
You go in there,it'll ruin the whole illusion of the party.
你还是带着你的威士忌回去…
Take your scotch back in there...
…然后我去帮你拿香烟 好吗？
...and I will get your cigarettes for you,sir.
还有我的眼镜 包在我身上
-Get my glasses too. -All righty-roo.
真是第一次说那句话的好时机
What a great moment to say that for the first time.
我现在来看看 第一个人的最尴尬的回忆就是…
Okay,the first person's most embarrassing memory is...
…“莫妮卡，你的派对真逊”
... "Monica,your party sucks."
非常幽默
Very funny.
天啊，有人忘了用杯垫吗？
Oh,no! Did someone forget to use a coaster?
什么？
What?
我没有看到呀
I don't see anything.
是吗？我又看见水环了
Great,I'm seeing water rings again.
罗斯，那是谁的眼镜啊？
Ross,whose glasses are those?
我的
Mine.
你戴远近两用的眼镜？
You wear bifocals?
我的视力…
I have a condition apparently...
…显然同时…
...that I require...
…需要用到两种镜片
...two different sets of focals.
你知道我先生也有一副 跟你一样的眼镜吗？
Do you know my husband has glasses just like that?
那种眼睛很流行
Well,those are very popular frames.
尼尔希达卡（60年代歌星）也有一副
Neil Sedaka wears them.
听说你有办法弄我们出去 是不是？
I hear you can get people out of here.
你并没有告诉我你男友会抽烟
You didn't tell me your boyfriend smokes.
对，像根烟囱
Yeah,like a chimney.
大烟客
Big smoker.
超大烟客
Big,big smoker.
事实上，我现在就去走廊上 点燃这个坏小子了
In fact,I'm gonna go into the hallway and fire up this bad boy.
你在戴我的眼镜吗？
Are you wearing my glasses?
对
Yes.
我只是在替你 把那个耳架弄暖一点
I was just warming up the earpieces for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是我的香烟吗？
Is that one of my cigarettes?
对，没错 我在把这个烟屁股弄湿
Yes,it is. I was just moistening the tip.
好了，她去倒垃圾了 我可以弄你们出去了
She's taking the trash out,so I can get you out of here.
可是你们得马上走 她随时会回来
But it has to be now. She'll be back any minute.
那我朋友呢？
What about my friend?
不行，只有你们三个 超过三个她就会起疑心的
Only the three of you. Any more and she'll get suspicious.
好吧，我去拿外套 没有时间了
-Let me just get my coat. -There isn't time!
什么都不要拿
Just leave everything.
隔壁那些人会照顾你们的
They'll take care of you next door.
他们真的有啤酒吗？
Is it true they have beer?
你听到的都是真的
Everything you've heard is true.
你们小声一点，好不好？
Could you guys please keep it down?
我们要来个拼字锦标赛
We're trying to start a Boggle tournament.
如果大家发现要玩拼字游戏
If people find out they're playing spelling games...
我们这里的人就会都去她那边了
...there'll be nobody left here.
你
You!
还有你
And you.
你们应该在我的派对的啊
You're supposed to be at my party.
还有甘瑟
And Gunther!
你在这个地方干什么啊？
What are you doing here?
欢迎来到…
Welcome to the fo
好吧，对不起嘛 可是这些人需要我啊
All right,I'm sorry. But these people needed me.
他们辛苦了一个礼拜 今天是周六
They work hard all week. It's Saturday night.
他们有权享一点儿乐的，去
They deserve to have a little fun. Go!
我的派对很好玩
You know,my party is fun.
或许是安静了一点吧 比较含蓄的乐趣
It's a little quieter,less obvious sort of fun.
但如果大家给它一个机会 那会比较…
But if people would just give it a chance,it's
你要我去看心理医生？ 亲爱的，你显然有问题了
-You want me to see a therapist? -Sweetheart,you have a problem.
你居然选了一个 跟你爸一模一样的男朋友
You've chosen a boyfriend exactly like your father.
妈，我会先去预约的
Okay,Mom,I'll make an appointment.
现在我得走了 我得去做一件事
But right now,I gotta go. I gotta go do a thing.
你知道吗？你老妈居然花了 一千二百块买一个盆栽
Did you know your mother spent $1200 on bonsai trees?
我觉得我好像格列佛在小人国里（《格列佛游记》）
I felt like Gulliver.
爸，你知道吗？ 我真的很想再多听，真的…
Daddy,I really want to hear more about this...
…但我有点事要处理
...but I just have to do some stuff.
我一直很努力 想要挽救我们的婚姻…
You work and you work and you work at a marriage...
…可是他只关心他那艘蠢船
... but all he cares about is his stupid boat.
我一直一直努力的去弄我的船
You work and you work and you work on a boat.
他老是嘲笑我的烧陶课
He always ridiculed my pottery classes.
磨好了之后还要上釉
And you sand it and varnish it.
但他还是用我做的杯子喝东西
But when all is said and done,he still drinks out of the mugs.
听她唠叨一晚她的瑜珈 还有她的《廊桥遗梦》…
One night of her yoga and Bridges of Madison County....
威士忌，香烟… 盆栽和吉娃娃狗…
-The scotch,the cigarettes.... - The bonsais and the Chihuahua....
我或许只看了 三个礼拜的心理医生，但…
I may have only been in therapy for three weeks now but
她要半条船干什么？
What the hell does she want with half a boat?
好啦好啦，你穿着衣服我光着身子好了
Okay,okay,you can be shirts and I'll be skins.
我光身子呀
I'll be skins!
你没事吧，老虎？
How you holding up there,tiger?
很抱歉，我父母在闹离婚时 很多人叫我“老虎”
Sorry. When my parents were getting divorced,I got a lot of "tigers."
很多人叫我 “冠军”“领袖”“体育委员”
I got a lot of "champs," "chiefs," "sports."
还有人叫我“州长”
I even got a "governor."
就这样了，是不是？ 我的生活就会变成这样
This is it,isn't it? This is what my life will be like.
我妈在那边，我爸在那边
My mom there,my dad there.
感恩节，圣诞节
Thanksgiving,Christmas.
她得到房子，他住在我妹用柳条家具帮他布置的公寓
She gets the house,he's in a condo my sister will decorate with wicker.
钱德，你是怎么熬过来的？
How did you get through this?
我依靠我精心策划的计划…
I relied on a carefully regimented program...
…拒绝面对现实…
...of denial...
…还有尿床
...and wetting the bed.
这太诡异了
You know,I just It's so weird.
我是说，我人在里面 却听着他们两个人骂来骂去
I mean,I was in there just listening to them bitch about each other.
可是心里却一直在想着七月四号国庆日
All I kept thinking about was the Fourth of July.
因为那让你想起我们的祖先…
Because it reminded you of the way...
…从前也是骂来骂去的吗？
...our forefathers used to bitch at each other?
是这样子的啦 我们每年…
It's just this thing. Every year we would...
…都会坐我爸的船出海 去看烟火
...go out on my dad's boat and watch the fireworks.
可是我妈讨厌去 因为海风会把她的头发吹膨
Mom always hated it because the ocean air made her hair all big.
我妹妹吉儿 则会靠在船边呕吐…
My sister Jill would be throwing up over the side...
…我爸会不高兴 因为没有人帮他忙
...and Dad would be upset because nobody helped.
当我们帮忙的时候呢 他又会吼叫说我们做得不对
And when we did help,he'd scream at us for doing it wrong.
但是当烟火开始的时候 大家都闭嘴了
But then when the fireworks started,everybody just shut up.
然后天气会变得很冷
You know,and it'd get really cold.
我们会全部都挤在 一条毯子下面
And we'd all just sort of smoosh under this one blanket.
从来没有人想到要多带一条来
It never occurred to anybody to bring another one.
但是现在…
And now it's....
对，我知道
Yeah,I know.
谢谢光临，希望你们玩得开心
Thanks for coming. I hope you had fun.
好了，我要走了
All right,I'm hitting the road.
我把十个动词放在你桌上了
Now,I've left my 10 verbs on the table.
一定要把完成的诗寄给我
Be sure and send me that finished poem.
我会的，很高兴你来了
Okay,will do. Glad you came.
我想我看到瑞秋在走廊上 我去看看
-I think I saw Rachel out in the hall. -Let me go check.
你妈要跟你道别了
Your mom wants to say goodbye.
生日快乐，亲爱的
Happy birthday,sweetie.
小心开车
You drive safe.
罗斯，你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我正在为去滑水做准备
I'm getting ready for the water skiing.
来呀，抱抱
Okay,big hug. One more. Come on!
你好吗？
How are you?
格林医生，你要去哪里？ 拿我的外套
-Where are you going? -To get my coat.
我们去拿
We'll get that for you.
好了…我可以自己去，好吗？
All right,all right. I can get my own coat.
抱歉，馅饼让我们爽歪了
Sorry,we're on a major flan high.
不对…你不应该来这里的
Oh,no. No,you're not supposed to be here.
因为这里是准备区 全弄错了，你应该走
This is the staging area. It's all wrong. You should leave.
出去就是了
You know,just get out.
要不要来杯薄荷甜酒啊（法语）？
Or perhaps you'd like a creme de menthe.
我必须回我的“法国庄园”了，谢了
I have to be heading toward my chateau.
好吧，那么我猜 我们又要回到走廊了
I guess we're going back into the hallway again.
谢谢光临，格林太太
Thanks for coming,Mrs. Greene.
保重了
You take care.
你们这些孩子
Oh,you kids.
那么…
Well.
好久没有参加这么棒的派对了
This is the best party I've been to in years.
谢谢
Thank you!
各位，切馅饼了
Okay,everybody,it's time for flan!
对，准备享用凝胶的乐趣了
Yep! Get ready for the gelatinous fun.
看起来有点像伤口感染时的样子
Looks like that stuff you get when you get an infection.
好了，够了
Okay,that's enough.
瑞秋，许个馅饼愿吧
Okay,Rachel,make a special flan wish.
好了
Okay,I've got one.
小心！
Heads up!
哇哦，愿望很少有实现的时候
Wow! Those things almost never come true.